OSUYA CHARLES

Ajah Lagos, Nigeria (2704)| +2348149592750 | +2348120854426| aolfiligre@gmail.com

Professional Summary

Resourceful software development professional, driven to increase team effectiveness. Focused on usability and performance improvements. Known for creating useful, efficient and cost-effective projects. Skilled in directing development with creative and performance-oriented approach.

With over 3 years developing different web applications, I've worked in diverse sectors ranging from Medical, Accounting, and Journalism.

Skills

- Solutions Deployment
- Complex -Problem Solver
- Api Design
- MongoDb
- Vuejs
- Vuex
- Nodejs
- Javascript

- Go (Gorilla Mux)
- Dashboard Creation and Charts(Chart is,

D3, ZingCharts, etc)

- Web Application Development
- React Native
- Flutter
- Git
- Express, Sails

Work History

Software Engineer

Nov 2019- February 2020 London, London

Deepview

- Wrote highly maintainable, solid code in JavaScript for DeepView platform that formed core framework and has won consistent praise from subsequent developers
- Worked with project managers, developers, quality assurance and customers to resolve technical issues
- Researched, designed and implemented scalable applications for information identification, extraction, analysis, retrieval and indexing
- Worked closely with software development and testing team members to design and develop robust

- solutions to meet client requirements for functionality, scalability and performance
- Managed front-end code base developed with Sails JS, using Vue-JS as templating Engine
- Optimized system performance by making proactive adjustments and resolving bugs

Frontend Engineer

May 2019- November 2019

Freyda

London, London

- Designed and implemented frontend solution for both the team website and core dashboard application using vuejs
- Consumed endpoints from python backend that extracted contents from pdf files, and displayed them on the front end
- Implemented Charts features using D3.js, and chart js from python backend
- Worked with project managers, Ui designers, developers to contribute on the overall nature and design sense of the dashboard

Frontend Engineer

January 2018 - April 2019

Demz- Analytics/ Bloverse

Ajah, Lagos

- Designed pixel perfect frontend codes to match UI designs
- Worked on Demz-analytics website, as well as Landing page using
- Collaborated with other team members to develop frontend features (Component library, mixins, slots, etc) for front-end solution
- Consumed endpoints from Adonis backend, and made sure the functionality matched teh system requirements
- Worked on bubble representation of features using D3.js

IT/ Systems Engineer

February 2015 - December 2017

Emaris Systems Limited / Doren Specialist Hospital

Ajah, Lagos

- Managing and monitoring all installed systems and infrastructure including system routing and configuration
- Installed, configuring, testing and maintaining operating systems, application software and system management tools (MEDIX)
- Maintain security, backup, and redundancy strategies
- Write and maintain custom scripts to increase system efficiency and lower the human intervention time on any tasks
- Tackled networking solutions, with wamp and c# integration

- Monitor and test application performance for potential bottlenecks, identify possible solutions, and work with developers to implement those fixes
- Documentation of Core Management solution (MEDIX)

Education/Service

Bsc Computer Science and Information Technology

Nov 2010 - May 2015

Bowen University Iwo

Osun State, Nigeria

National Youth Service Corps

May 2015 - March 2016

Koko/Besse Local Government

Kebbi State